You can now generate AI videos with
现在您可以生成具有
consistent characters. No more random
一致角色的AI视频。 不再出现随机
faces or awkward rerenders. Runway just
面孔或尴尬的重新渲染。  Runway刚刚
dropped their new references feature,
推出了新的参考资料功能，
and here's exactly how to use it before
以下是它的具体使用方法，抢先一步了解一下
anyone else. Now, quick disclaimer.
。 现在，先做个简短的免责声明。
Runway is moving fast, but is not
Runner项目进展迅速，但尚未
perfect yet. It's one of the most
完美。 它是目前市面上最
userfriendly tools out there for video
易于使用的视频
generation. But if you're coming from
生成工具之一。 但如果你之前用过像
something like Pika, you might notice
Pika 这样的游戏，你可能会注意到
that Runway's motion is a little more,
Runway 的动作更偏向于
let's say, artsy than accurate. Just
艺术性，而不是精确性。
think vibe first over frame perfect. But
氛围比画面完美更重要。 但这不
that's also part of the charm, right?
也是它的魅力所在吗？
Especially for stylized or conceptual
尤其适用于风格化或概念化的
visuals. Here's the current workflow.
视觉效果。 以下是当前的工作流程。
Runway's references feature only works
Runway 的引用功能目前仅适用于
inside text to image for now. So you
文本转图像功能。 所以你现在还
can't just feed in a prompt and
不能简单地输入提示和
reference and get a full video just yet.
参考信息就获得完整的视频。
Instead, you upload up to three
相反，您可以上传最多三张
reference images to guide the generation
参考图像，以指导生成
of a consistent still image. Then you
一致的静态图像。 然后
animate that still using the
使用
imagetovideo tool. So yeah, it's a
图像转视频工具将静态图像制作成动画。 是的，这是一个
two-step process, but a powerful one. So
两步过程，但效果显著。
step one, generate your consistent
第一步，打造你的统一
image. In Gen 4, go to text to image tab
形象。 在 Gen 4 中，转到文本转图像选项卡，
and click on references. Now before we
然后单击参考文献。 在
select any references, quickly we'll
选择任何参考文献之前，我们先快速地在
select our output dimensions here. And
这里选择输出尺寸。
then we can use this aesthetic range
然后，我们可以使用此美学范围
slider to increase or decrease the
滑块来增加或减少
amount of style variation we'll see
我们在四组图像之间看到的风格变化量
generations. Upload up to three
。 上传最多三张拍摄
subject. No heavy shadows, no
对象正面朝向、光线均匀的照片。 没有浓重的阴影，没有
sunglasses, no wild backgrounds. Keep it
太阳镜，也没有杂乱的背景。 保持
clean and focus to be safe. Now, here's
清洁，注意安全。 现在，
where most people fumble. the prompt.
大多数人都会在这里犯错。 提示。
You need to align your reference image
你需要将参考图像
with a descriptive cinematic prompt. Try
与描述性的电影提示语相匹配。 试试这样的
something like this. A cinematic
方法。 一幅电影般的
portrait of a woman wearing a red jacket
肖像画，描绘了一位身穿红色外套的女子
standing in a foggy forest. Dramatic
站在雾气弥漫的森林中。 戏剧性的
sidelighting, shallow depth of field.
侧光，浅景深。
The AI works best when both the image
当图像
and the prompt speak the same visual
和提示语使用相同的视觉
language. Now, if I'm being totally
语言时，人工智能的效果最佳。 说
honest, it could be a prompt issue, but
实话，这可能是一个紧急问题，但这
three out of the four of these look
四个里面有三个看起来
pretty ass, but I think this one will
很糟糕，但我认为这个应该
work. Now, once you've got your
行得通。 现在，一旦你
character locked in, it's time to
确定了角色，就可以开始
animate. So, for step two, this is where
制作动画了。 那么，第二步，
the fun starts. Now, you're prompting
好戏就要开始了。 现在，你是在推动
movement and not just aesthetics. Try
行动，而不仅仅是追求美观。 试试这样的
something like this. Camera slowly
方法。 镜头缓缓
pushing in as she turns her head
推进，她
slightly and fog swirls in the
微微转过头，背景中雾气缭绕
background. Now, the better your
。 显然，你的
directional language, obviously, the
指示性语言表达得越好，
better your results. Think like a
结果就越好。 像
cinematographer and not just a prompt
电影摄影师一样思考，而不仅仅是像提手
engineer. At least that's what helps me.
工程师一样思考。 至少这对我很有帮助。
Now, here's a fair critique. Runways
现在，让我来做一个公正的评价。 跑道
animation can sometimes feel a bit
动画有时会感觉有点
floaty or abstract, especially compared
飘忽或抽象，尤其是
to tools like Pika, which tend to
与 Pika 等工具相比，后者往往会
produce snappier and more grounded
产生更流畅、更贴近现实的
motion. But again, it depends on your
动作。 但话说回来，这取决于你的
style. Runway shines in those dreamlike
风格。  Runway 在那些梦幻般的
cinematic moments, and it's still one of
电影时刻中大放异彩，它仍然是
the best platforms for creators who want
创作者想要
control without learning Blender or
掌控一切但又不想学习 Blender 或
training another model entirely. So,
训练另一个模型的最佳平台之一。 所以，
here's one of my favorite new ways to
这里介绍一下我最喜欢的
use this tool. So, I have this location
使用这个工具的新方法之一。 所以，我这里有位置
reference and model reference here. And
参考和模型参考。
if I select them both, I can then label
如果我同时选中它们，我就可以给它们贴上标签，
them and then tag them in my prompt and
然后在提示中标记它们，并
just write something like show me at
写一些类似“在
model 2 in location 2 and then
位置 2 的模型 2 中显示”之类的内容，然后
regenerate it. And once I do that, I get
重新生成它。 完成之后，我会得到
some pretty cool custom results in the
一些非常酷的自定义结果，以
form of an image that we can use the
图像的形式呈现，我们可以使用
same workflow from earlier to turn into
之前相同的工作流程将其转换为
a custom video like so. So, here are a
自定义视频，如下所示。 以下是
few pro tips to help you get started.
一些专业技巧，可以帮助您入门。
Don't stylize your reference images.
不要对参考图片进行风格化处理。
Keep them natural. Use consistent
保持自然状态。 为了获得最佳效果，请在上传的照片中使用一致的
outfits and lighting across your uploads
服装和光线
for the best results. And if you're
。 如果你
planning a multi-shot sequence, generate
计划制作多镜头序列，
all your stills first, then animate them
请先生成所有静态图像，然后逐一制作动画，
one by one to keep your character
以保持角色在各个
consistent across cuts. Now, Runway has
镜头之间的一致性。 现在，Runway 已
confirmed that references will soon
确认，参考资料将很快
expand to support full-on texttovideo
扩展到支持完整的文本转视频
workflows. But until then, this two-step
工作流程。 但在此之前，这种两步
process is your best bet for character
法是实现角色一致性的最佳选择，而且
consistency without a steep learning
学习曲线不会太陡峭
curve. So, jump in now while it's still
。 所以，趁着热度还没过去，赶紧加入吧，
fresh and before everyone starts posting
免得大家都开始
these same five AI characters on
在 Instagram 上发布这五个 AI 角色
Instagram. And if this helped, like,
。 如果这对你有帮助，请点赞、
subscribe, and let me know what scene or
订阅，并告诉我
character you're planning to build with
你打算用《
references from Runway. And with that
Runway》中的素材来创作什么场景或角色。 就这样
being said, peace.
，愿世界和平。